Marco Juliani <u>portfolio</u> <u>github</u> <u>linkedin</u> <u>gmail</u> <u>twitter</u>

Summary

Technologist combining software engineering expertise with architectural design thinking to solve problems. Unique blend of 5 years in software development and 5 years in architectural design, specializing in computational modeling and optimization. Interested in web development, spatial computing, parametric modelling, embeddings + LLM applications, machine learning, optimization algorithms, among others.

Professional Experience

10/2022 - 12/2024 NY Senior Software Engineer <u>Outer Labs</u>

- Developed **full-stack** prototypes as we iterated over our product vision during pre-seed phase of a real estate startup
- Played an important role in defining and future-proofing the data model and driving alignment across eng + product
- Evaluated 10+ external data services and built ETL pipelines processing 1M records weekly for real estate data ingestion
- Led **RAG** experiments and built a **backend service** enabling engineering/product teams to prototype and evaluate **LLM workflows**
- Coordinated API and data model integration between 2 teams to remove undesirable dependencies
- Played key role in defining the **event loop** of new **space planning web application**
- Contributed to critical libraries across the app related to rendering, state management, spatial algorithms, and geometric operations

04/2021 - 10/2022 London Software Developer KOPE

- Led the development and client engagement to deliver a **modular building configurator** implementing complex **adjacency** and **stacking** rulesets specific to the client's proprietary system
- Contributed to algorithm development and overall implementation during strategic pilot engagements related to building enclosure systems
- Mentored younger engineers on best practices and design patterns

02/2020 - 04/2021 London Computational Design Specialist <u>CallisonRTKL</u>

- Authored custom plugins for Rhino + Grasshopper relating to the analysis and feasibility of building proposals
- Authored **parametric tooling** for the analysis of **multi-objective** tradeoffs of a commercial development
- Implemented a logging system for tracking usage of our internal tooling initiatives across the firm

Education

09/2018 - 05/2019 London MSc Architectural Computation <u>UCL Bartlett</u>

Computer-science-for-architects program where we:

- learned object-oriented-programming, familiarized ourselves with Visual Studio and Git
- leveraged **Unity** and **C#** as a prototyping and simulation environment
- implemented vanilla L-Systems, Genetic Algorithms, Kohonen Nets, Artificial Neural Networks, Octrees.

08/2008 - 05/2013 Tucson Bachelor's of Architecture <u>University of Arizona</u>	
--	--

Skills

Frontend	Javascript, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, MUI, Tailwind
Rendering + Browser	Canvas API, Three.js, R3F, Pixi.js, Canvas-Sketch, Chrome API
Maps + Geospatial	Mapbox, Google Maps Platform, PostGIS
API + Scripting	Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Python, Flask, Go, C#, GraphQL
Database + ORM + Object Storage	Postgres, Firebase, Firestore, GCS, MySQL, IndexDB, TypeORM, Drizzle, Yjs, Liveblocks
DevOps + Infrastructure	Gitlab, Azure DevOps, Github, GCP, AWS, Docker
Product Lifecycle	Agile, TDDs, Docusaurus, Slack, GSuite, Linear, Notion
Data & Tools	Data Models, Mermaid, ETL Pipelines, DuckDB, Visidata
LLMs & ML Libraries / Frameworks	RAG, Function-Calling, Haystack, LLama-Index, Pytorch, Numpy
Algorithms	GAs, L-Systems, Kohonen Nets, Neural Nets, Octrees
Computational Design	Rhinoceros, Grasshopper, Revit, Dynamo, Unity

Involvement

08/2024	Competition	Untabbed: <u>Gemini API Developer Competition</u>
04/2021	<u>Publication</u>	Rumoer 76: voxel-based building + apartment generator mentioned in <i>Generative Design With Hypar</i> article (pg. 43).
05/2020	iOS game	Grid-locked: foray into game development during lockdown
04/2020	<u>Talk</u>	Data Management & Display: <u>Elefront</u> and <u>Human UI</u>
01/2020	<u>Plugin</u>	PlanBee for Grasshopper: cell-based spatial analysis plugin.
08/2019	Tutoring	Bartlett: Introduction to Programming Workshop (1) (2)